Finding Aid for the Norris Hundley Papers LSC.0577
UCLA Library Special Collections
Norris Hundley papers
1794-2010
1960-2010
UCLA Library Special Collections
Hundley, Norris, Jr., 1935-2013
LSC.0577
39.2 Linear Feet (94 boxes, 3 shoe boxes, and 1 oversize box)
Collection consists of correspondence and research files related to Norris Hundley's editorship of the Pacific Historical Review, the case of City of Los Angeles vs. City of San Fernando et al., and his various publications. Additional materials include lecture slides and photographs. Other materials are related to his activities as a professor at UCLA.
94 boxes, 3 shoes boxes, and 1 oversize box (39.2 linear ft.)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Subseries 1A, Pacific Historical Review correspondence is closed until 2020.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS UNPROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Norris Hundley, Jr.; gift; 1998. Carol Hundley; gift; 2015.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9950855473606533
Biography/History
Norris Hundley, Jr. was born on October 26, 1935 in Houston, Texas. He received his AB from Whittier College in 1958, and his PhD from the University of California, Los Angeles in 1963. His long and distinguished teaching career began as a professor of American history at the University of Houston (1963-1964), and then continued at UCLA (1964-1994), where he became professor emeritus of American history in 1994. As a scholar, he authored over a hundred books and essays, including several groundbreaking works on the history of water usage in California and the West. He is best known for his work on Western water rights, particularly The Great Thirst: Californians and Water, 1770s-1990s (1992). He co-authored one of only two books on the St. Francis Dam disaster of 1928 in the Santa Clarita Valley. Hundley was also the editor of the Pacific Historical Review for 29 years (1968-1997), during which time the journal took a leading role in the development of environmental and ethnic studies. He held leadership positions in many historical organizations, including the Western History Association (president, 1994-1995) and the American Historical Association, Pacific Coast Branch (president, 1994-1995). In addition, Hundley served as the director of the UCLA Latin American Center from 1989-1994, chair of the UCLA Program on Mexico from 1981-1994, and sat on various boards and committees related to the history of California and water usage rights. The last book he co-authored, Heavy Ground: William Mulholland and the St. Francis Dam Disaster (2015), was published posthumously and remains the authoritative text on the St. Francis Dam disaster. Hundley passed away on April 28, 2013.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of peer review files for the Pacific Historical Review (PHR), chiefly correspondence, and materials related to the research and publication of The Great Thirst (1992, 2000 revised edition) and Water and the West (2009, second edition). Files include extensive exhibits, transcripts, and filings from The City of Los Angeles vs. The City of San Fernando, et al., a major pueblo water rights case which included the cities of Glendale, Burbank, and others, and established precedent for water rights pertaining to the Los Angeles River. The exhibits for the case include copies of Spanish and Mexican documents from the Los Angeles City Archives and the Department of Water and Power, in addition to copies of early case material and texts. Materials used for the revised edition of The Great Thirst and Water and the West include extensive clippings and research files, and several reels of microfilm containing documents from the Library of Congress and the National Archives. The collection also includes fifty-five 3.5 inch floppy disks and six CDs, containing correspondence, manuscripts, research, interviews, slide photographs, and photographs. Other materials include reports, correspondence, and personal accounts related to Hundley's activities as a UCLA professor, such as the firing of Angela Davis in 1970 and a group of UCLA historians that wen to the 1965 March on Montgomery. Lastly, the collection contains numerous water usage project reports from California and other parts of the West. The PHR correspondence is sealed until 2020 to protect the confidentiality of contributors and reviewers.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Correspondence, 1959-2010, subseries A-B as follows:
Pacific Historical Review, 1968-1997
UCLA and miscellaneous, 1959-2010
City of Los Angeles vs. City of San Fernando, et al., circa 1794-1975, subseries A-D as follows:
Indexes, circa 1970
Indexed exhibits, circa 1800-1970
Miscellaneous exhibits, circa 1794-1958
Filings, 1969-1975
The Great Thirst and other publications, circa 1808-2009, subseries A-E as follows:
Clippings, 1973-2007
Microfilm, slides, negatives, and photographs, 1920-1999
Research files, circa 1808-2009
Reviews, 1966-2002
Digital materials, 1994-2005
Water projects and reports, 1974-2003, subseries A-N as follows:
All-American Canal Lining Project, 1994
Cadiz Groundwater Storage, circa 1999
CalFed Bay-Delta Program, 1998-1999
California State Water Project, 1974-1994
California Water Plan, 1989-2000
Central Valley Improvement Act, 1997-1999
Colorado River Report, 1988-2003
Imperial Irrigation District, 1997
Los Vaqueros Reservoir Enlargement, 1997
Lower Owens River Project, 1997
Salton Sea Restoration Project, 2000
Shasta Dam and Reservoir, 1997-1998
Southern California's Integrated Water Resources Plan, 1996
Urban Water Management Plan for the City of Los Angeles, 1995
Other activities, 1965-2007
Items Removed from the Collection
A bibliography of articles removed from the Norris Hundley Collection has been added to the collection file. Available upon request at the UCLA Library Special Collections.
Water -- Law and legislation -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Water rights -- California -- History -- Archives.; Periodical editors -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Historians -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Hundley, Norris, Jr.--Archives.; University of California, Los Angeles. Department of History--Faculty -- Archives
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1959-2010
  Scope and Contents note
  The series includes correspondence. Subseries 1A is sealed until 2020 to protect the confidentiality of contributors. In keeping with Dr. Hundley's original filing system, in subseries 1A folders are organized chronologically and then by the last name of the correspondent, and in subseries 1B folders are organized by the last name of the correspondent. Subseries 1B also contains nine 3.5 inch floppy disks which contain additional correspondence and letters of recommendation.
  Arranged in two subseries:
  1A. Pacific Historical Review, 1968-1997
  1B. UCLA and miscellaneous, 1959-2010
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - Subseries 1A: Pacific Historical Review, 1968-1997
    Correspondence between Norris Hundley and various editors. Additional materials are correspondence between Hundley, the UCLA administration and Professor Eugene Weber, the Department of History chairman, regarding funding and support for the Pacific Historical Review.
    General note
    Sealed until 2020.
    - A - Z, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4)
      - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - B (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - C (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Cities issue, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - D (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - E (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Editorial policies, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - F (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - G (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - H (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - I (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Indian issues, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 5-8)
        - ., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
        - ., 1970 May-September (Box 2, Folder 6)
        - ., 1970 October-December (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - ., 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - J (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - K (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - L (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - M (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - N (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - O (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Oil, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
      - P (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - R (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - S (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - T (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - U (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - V (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - W (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - XYZ (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - A - Z, 1973 (Box 4, Box 5, Box 6)
      - A (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - B (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - C (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - D (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - E (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - F (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - G (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - H (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - I - J (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - K (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - L (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - M (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - N (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - O (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - P (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Q (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - R (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - S (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - T (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - U - V (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - W (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - XYZ (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - A - Z, 1974 (Box 6, Box 7, Box 8, Box 9)
      - A (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - B (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - C (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - D (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - E (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - F (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - G (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - H (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - I (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - J (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - K (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - L (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - M (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - N (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - O (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - P (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - R (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - S (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - T (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - U - V (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - W (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - XYZ (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - A - Z, 1975 (Box 9, Box 10, Box 11)
      - A (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - B (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - C (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - D (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - E (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - F (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - G (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - H (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - I - J (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - K (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - L (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - M (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - N (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - O (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - P (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - R (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - S (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - T (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - U (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - V (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - W (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - XYZ (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - A - Z, 1976 (Box 11, Box 12, Box 13, Box 14)
      - A (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - B (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - C (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - D (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - E (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - F (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - G (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - H (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - I (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - J (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - K (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - L (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - M (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - N (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - O (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - P (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Q - R (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - S (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - T (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - U - V (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - W (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - XYZ (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - A - Z, 1977 (Box 14, Box 15, Box 16)
      - A (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - B (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - C (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - D (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - E (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - F (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - G (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - H (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - I (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - J (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - K (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - L (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - M (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - N (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - O (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - P (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Q - R (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - S (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - T (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - U - V (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - W (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - XYZ (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - A - Z, 1978 (Box 16, Box 17)
      - A (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - B (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - C (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - D (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - E (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - F (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - G (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - H (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - I - J (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - K (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - L (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - M (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - N - O (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - P (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Q - R (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - S (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - T (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - U - V (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - W (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - XYZ (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - A - Z, 1979 (Box 18, Box 19)
      - A (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - B (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - C (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - D (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - E - F (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - G (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - H (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - I - J (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - K (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - L (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - M (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - N (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - O - P (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Q - R (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - S (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - T (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - U - V (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - W (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - XYZ (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - A - Z, 1980 (Box 19, Box 20)
      - A (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - B (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - C (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - D (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - E - F (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - G (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - H (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - I - J (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - K (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - L (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - M (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - N (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - O (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - P (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Q - R (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - S (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - T (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - U - V (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - W (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - XYZ (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - A - Z, 1981 (Box 21, Box 22)
      - A (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - B (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Burr, Weber, and Burke, 1974-1981 (Box 82, Folder 1-2)
      - C (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - D (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - E - F (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - G (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - H (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - I - J (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - K (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - L (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - M (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - N - O (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - P (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Q - R (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - S (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - T (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - V (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - W - Z (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - A - Z, 1982-1983 (Box 22, Box 23, Box 24)
      - A (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - B (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - C (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - D (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - E - F (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - G (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - H (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - I - J (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - K (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - L (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - M (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - N - O (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - P (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Q - R (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - S (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - T (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - V (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - W (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - XYZ (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - A - Z, 1984 (Box 24, Box 25)
      - A (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - B (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - C (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - D (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - E - F (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - G (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - H (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - I - J (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - K - L (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - M (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - N - O (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - P (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - R (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - S (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - T (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - U - V (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - W - Z (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - A - Z, 1985-1986 (Box 26, Box 27, Box 28)
      - A (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - B (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - C (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - D (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - E (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - F (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - G (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - H (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - I (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - J (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - K (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - L (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - M (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - N (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - O (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - P (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Q - R (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - S (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - T (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - U - V (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - W (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - XYZ (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - A - Z, 1987-1988 (Box 29, Box 30, Box 31)
      - A (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - B (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - C (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - D (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - E (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - F (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - G (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - H (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - I (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - J (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - K (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - L (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - M (Box 30, Folder 4-5)
      - N (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - O (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - P (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - R (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - S (Box 31, Folder 2-4)
      - T (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - V (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - W (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - XYZ (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - A - W, 1989-1990 (Box 32, Box 33, Box 34)
      There is no X-Z in this subseries.
      - A (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - B (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - C (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - D (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - E (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - F (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - G (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - H (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - I (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - J (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - K (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - L (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - M (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
      - N - O (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - P (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - R (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - S (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - T (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - U - V (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - W (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - A - Z, 1991-1992 (Box 34, Box 35, Box 36)
      - A (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - B (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - C (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - D (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - E - F (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - G (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - H (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - I (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - J (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - K (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - L (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - M (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - N - O (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - P (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Q - R (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - S (Box 36, Folder 3-4)
      - T (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - U - V (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - W (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - XYZ (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - A - Z, 1993-1994 (Box 37, Box 38, Box 39)
      - A (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - B (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - C (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - D (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - E (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - F (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - G (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - H (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - I (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - J - K (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - L (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - M (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - N - O (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - P (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Q - R (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - S (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - T - U (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - V (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - W (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - XYZ (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - A - Z, 1995-1997 (Box 40, Box 41, Box 42)
      - A (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - B (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - C (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - D - E (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - F (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - G (Box 40, Folder 6)
      - H - I (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - J (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - K (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - L (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - M (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - N - O (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - P (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - R (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - S (Box 42, Folder 2-3)
      - T (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - U (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - V (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - W (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - XYZ (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 1B: UCLA and miscellaneous, 1959-2010
    Assorted correspondence with administrators, peers, and colleagues regarding Dr. Hundley's position as a professor at UCLA. Subjects include Hundley's participation in Martin Luther King Jr.'s March on Montgomery and UCLA's support for the Pacific Historical Review. The subseries contains some photographs and nine 3.5 inch floppy disks.
    - A, 1964-2005 (Box 82, Folder 3-4, Box 43, Folder 1)
    - B, 1964-2005; 1964-1980 (Box 82, Folder 5-6, Box 43, Folder 2)
    - C, 1964-1999 (Box 83, Folder 1-2, Box 43, Folder 3)
    - D, 1965-1990 (Box 43, Folder 4, Box 83, Folder 3)
    - E, 1965-1994 (Box 43, Folder 5, Box 83, Folder 4)
    - F, 1964-1997 (Box 43, Folder 6, Box 83, Folder 5)
    - G, 1964-1997 (Box 43, Folder 7, Box 83, Folder 6, Box 84)
    - H, 1964-1999 (Box 44, Folder 1, Box 84, Folder 2)
    - I, 1975-2007 (Box 84, Folder 4, Box 44, Folder 2)
    - J, 1965-1998 (Box 84, Folder 5, Box 44, Folder 3)
    - K, 1975-2007 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - L, 1965-1997 (Box 44, Folder 5, Box 85, Folder 1-2)
    - M, 1964-2004 (Box 44, Folder 6, Box 85, Folder 3-5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1959-1964 (Box 44, Folder 7, Box 45, Folder 1)
      These files contain early correspondence regarding teaching positions and research interests.
    - N, 1964-2004 (Box 86, Folder 1, Box 45, Folder 2)
    - O, 1965-2000 (Box 86, Folder 2, Box 45, Folder 3)
    - P, 1964-2006; 1964-1993 (Box 86, Folder 3, Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Pacific Historical Review, 1976 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      Letters advocating UCLA's continued support for the Pacific Historical Review.
    - Powell book, 2006 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Q, 1984 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - R, 1964-2009 (Box 45, Folder 6, Box 86)
    - S, 1964-2002 (Box 45, Folder 7, Box 46, Folder 1, Box 86, Box 87, Folder 1-2)
    - T, 1964-1996 (Box 46, Folder 2, Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Thank you re: second edition of Water and the West, 1992-2009 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Tipton correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - U, 1964-2004 (Box 46, Folder 3, Box 87, Folder 6)
    - University of California Press, 1992-1995 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - V, 1967-1998 (Box 46, Folder 5, Box 87, Folder 7)
    - W, 1965-1994 (Box 88, Folder 1, Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Western History Association re: meeting, 2010 August (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - XYZ, 1965-1997 (Box 88, Folder 3, Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Digital materials, 1995-2007 (Box 94, Folder 1)
      Scope and Content
      This file includes nine 3.5 inch floppy disks which contain professional correspondence and letters of recommendation.
- Series 2: City of Los Angeles vs. City of San Fernando, et al, 1794-1975
  Case materials.
  Arranged in four subseries:
  2A. Indexes, ca. 1970.
  2B. Indexed exhibits, ca. 1800-1970.
  2C. Miscellaneous exhibits, ca. 1794-1970.
  2D. Filings, 1969-1975.
  - Subseries 2A: Indexes, circa 1970
    Various indexes and catalogs to the exhibits. Critical reference tools for the exhibits listed in Subseries 2B.
    - Index to exhibits, circa 1970 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      Index to the plaintiff's and defendant's pueblo rights exhibits used in City of Los Angeles vs. City of San Fernando, et al. Includes exhibits for the Plaintiff (LA), joint Defendants (D), San Fernando (SF), Glendale and Burbank (GB), and Crecenta Valley.
    - Analysis of exhibits, undated (Box 47, Folder 2)
      Analysis of pueblo rights evidence and exhibits. References the exhibits found in Subseries 2B.
    - Catalogue of exhibits, undated (Box 47, Folder 3)
      Catalogue of exhibits used in various pueblo rights cases.
      Location of old records.
      Relationship of boundaries to population.
    - Trial index, undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
      Volume One of the trial transcript and exhibit indexes.
      Covers pages 11374-19836 of the trial, relating to the pueblo rights issue.